American Brass Company Records 1997.0996
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series I: Historical Materials, undated, 1351-1978
  - Subseries C: Pope Subject Files, undated, 1351-1960
    - XYZ
      - "Yankee Iron" story, 1909-1952 (Box 3:22)
    - Newspaper clippings relating to American Brass, 1960-1962 (Box 4:23)
      - Advances in the brass industry
      - Acquisitions and expansions
      - Awards
      - Copper
      - Closures
      - Employee news
    - Newspaper clippings related to American Brass, 1960-1962 (Box 4:24)
      - History
      - Law
      - Miscellaneous
      - Politics
      - Unrelated news
      - Weather impacts
  - Subseries D: "History of the American Brass Company", undated, 1821-1954
    - "History of the American Brass Company" by C.S. Judd, 1900-1954 (Box 4:25)
    - "History of the American Brass Company" by C.S. Judd [Incomplete], 1900-1954 (Box 4:26)
    - Judd's manuscripts, 1900-1954 (Box 4:27)
    - Drafts and research data, 1824-1954
      - Chapters II-III (Box 4:28)
      - Chapter IV (Box 4:29)
      - Chapters V-VIII (Box 4:30)
    - Material from Judd's desk, 1950-1959 (Box 5:31)
      - notes for identifying photographs
      - notes pertaining to research
    - Research Material (Box 5:32)
      - Brass Manufacturers, undated
      - Cairns, Robert A., 1859, 1885
      - Draft, undated
      - Ledgers, 1844-1870
      - Mills
        - Bradleyville Iron mill, 1821-1936
        - Stone and copper mills, undated
      - Patents, 1924, 1926
      - Photograph listing, 1888-1910
    - "Early Trade Associations" by C.S. Judd, 1953 (Box 5:33)
    - "Sidelights on the Brass Mill Industry" by C.S. Judd, 1952 (Box 5:34)
  - Subseries E: Background and historical materials, undated, 1811-1955
    - American Flask and Cap Company, 1940-1952 (Box 5:35)
    - American Metal Hose Company, 1910-1949 (Box 5:35)
    - Ansonia Brass and Copper Company, 1869-1955 (Box 5:35)
    - Benedict and Burnham Manufacturing Company, 1811-1953 (Box 5:36)
    - Birmingham Brass Company, undated (Box 5:36)
    - Buffalo Copper and Brass Rolling Mills, 1939-1954 (Box 5:36)
    - Chicago Brass Company, 1905-1951 (Box 5:37)
    - Coe Brass Manufacturing Company, 1865-1950 (Box 5:37)
    - Detroit Copper and Brass Rolling Mills, 1939-1940 (Box 5:37)
    - French Manufacturing Company, 1939-1954 (Box 5:37)
    - Holmes, Booth and Haydens, 1851-1940 (Box 5:38)
    - Wallace and Sons (Box 5:38)
    - Waterbury Brass Company, 1856-1953 (Box 6:39)
    - Wolcottville Brass Company, 1940-1951 (Box 6:39)
- Series II: Administrative Files, undated, 1848-1972
  - Subseries A: Executive Minutes, 1911-1924
    - Opinion on Reorganization, 1911 (Box 6:40)
    - Executive Minutes, 1912 (Box 6:41)
    - Executive Minutes, 1913 (Box 6:42)
    - Executive Minutes, 1914 (Box 6:43)
    - Executive Minutes, 1915 (Box 6:44)
    - Executive Minutes, 1916 (Box 6:45)
    - Executive Minutes, 1917 (Box 6:46)
    - Executive Minutes, 1918 (Box 7:47)
    - Executive Minutes, 1919 (Box 7:48)
    - Executive Minutes, 1920 (Box 7:49)
    - Executive Minutes, 1921-1922 (Box 7:50)
    - Executive Minutes, 1923-1924 (Box 7:51)
  - Subseries B: Administrative files, 1863-1972
    - Board of Directors (Box 7:52)
      - Comparative statements of sales, 1963-1964
      - Estimated company income, 1964
      - Summary of minutes, 1964
    - Bylaws, charter, incorporation, 1893-1953 (Box 7:53)
    - Financial statements (Box 8:54)
      - Department earnings, 1919
      - Dividends paid, 1900-1944
      - Earnings of branches, 1942
      - Metal consumption, 1909-1934
      - Salaries, 1909
      - Sales - comparative statement, 1911-1914
      - Sales - total, 1900-1944
      - Statements, 1863-1944
      - Statements, 1912
    - Financial statements (Box 8:55)
      - Statements, 1913-1915
      - Summary of expenditures for real estate, 1900-1921
      - Treasurer's report, 1916, 1919
    - Meetings (Box 8:56)
      - Anaconda American Brass Co., special Meeting of the Board, 1972
      - Annual meeting of stockholders, 1971
      - Annual organization meeting of directors, 1971
    - Meetings (Box 8:57)
      - Board of directors, 1972
      - Directors annual meeting, 1970
      - Directors' organization by joint unanimous consent, 1972
      - Special meeting of board of directors, 1972
    - Merger of American Brass and Anaconda (Box 8:58)
      - Sales of Stock, 1916-1922
      - Deposit Agreements, 1921
      - Contracts between subscribers and Syndicate managers, 1921
    - Other Administrative Files (Box 8:59)
      - American Metal Hose Co., statement, 1909-1934
      - Ansonia Brass and Copper Co., Earnings by department, 1911
      - Coe Brass Manufacturing Co., Torrington account book, 1885-1887
      - Waterbury Homes Corp., Certificate of incorporation, 1916
    - Seamless Tube Association - minutes, 1906-1909 (Box 8:60)
    - Signatures, letterheads, company names compilation, 1907-1941 (Box 9:61)
    - Signatures, letterheads, company names compilation, 1904-1930 (Box 9:62)
    - Syndicate Agreements, 1921 (Box 9:63)
    - Terre Haute, Transfer of plant from ABC to American Aluminum, 1958 (Box 9:64)
    - Waterbury Brass Company (Box 9:65)
      - Amendment to articles of incorporation, 1865
      - General casting shop figures, 1910-1911
      - Statements, 1907-1909
    - Waterbury Brass Goods Corporation (Box 9:66)
      - Bylaws, 1934
      - Certificate of incorporation, 1904
      - Stockholders meetings and transfer of assets, 1911-1934
  - Subseries C: Departments and Warehouses, undated, 1848-1972
    - Cross section of metals, Coe Brass Mfg., 1905-1907, 1923 (Box 10:67)
    - Departmental duties, 1908-1910 (Box 10:68)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10:69)
      - "Aluminum and Aluminum Alloy Coiled Sheet", 1956
      - ABC Banquet Speech, 1918
      - Federal Cartridge Co., 1932
      - Finance Sheets, 1910-1919
      - Order request, 1905
      - Pension system, 1913, 1944
      - Pension for Theodore F. Van Zandt, 1956
      - Pope's chart of executive officers, 1942-1958
    - Oil mixtures (Box 10:70)
      - Book, 1913, 1920
      - Price sheet, undated
    - Periodical clippings regarding American Brass and Anaconda personnel, 1955-1960 (Box 10:71)
    - Patent Files (Box 10:72)
      - Patent No. 51.996, 1865-1869
      - Patent No. 70.252, 1868
      - Patent No. 73.409, 1872-1875
      - Patent No. 74.403, 1848
      - Patent No. 76.645, 1869
      - Patent No. 77.115, 1862-1872
      - Patent No. 77.620, 1862-1878
      - Patent No. 77.821, 1868-1875
    - Patent Files (Box 10:73)
      - Patent No. 78.978, 1868
      - Patent No. 80.137, 1868-1871
      - Patent No. 81.128, 1868-1873
      - Patent No. 81.370, 1872
      - Patent No. 82.480, 1868
      - Patent No. 83.874, 1868
      - Patent No. 85.697, 1870
    - Patent Files (Box 11:74)
      - Patent No. 93.391, 1868
      - Patent No. 93.661, 1869
      - Patent No. 95.110, 1869
      - Patent No. 97.298, 1869
    - Reports (Box 11:75)
      - ABC and subsidiaries annual report, 1928
      - Operating report, 1932-1939
      - Production department, 1929-1933
      - Technical department annual report, 1953
    - W.M. Moffat's file of assets (Anaconda), 1960 (Box 11:76)
    - General Foreman's notebook (Chas. Cooper) Torrington, 1895-1908 (Box 12)
  - Subseries D: Navy "E" Awards, 1863-1885, 1942-1945
    - Awards (Box 13)
      - Buffalo, NY plant, 1942
      - Torrington, Waterbury and Ansonia plants, 1942
      - Kenosha Brass Co., 1943
      - Detroit Branch, 1942
      - Anaconda Copper Mining Company, 1943
      - Anaconda Wire and Cable Co., Marion, IN plant, 1942
    - Articles
      - Clippings, speeches and pamphlets, 1942-1943 (Box 13:77)
      - Clippings, speeches and pamphlets, 1942-1945 (Box 13:78)
    - Coe Brass Manufacturing Company (Box 14)
      - Copybook, 1863-1864
      - Copybook, 1865-1867
      - Copybook, 1882-1885
      - Copybook, 1864-1883
  - Subseries E: Legal Records, 1848-1960
    - Closing Materials - French Mfg., American Metal Hose Co., Waterbury Brass Goods Corp., Ansonia Land and Water Power Co., 1927-1934 (Box 15:79)
    - E.M. Bleser (Box 15:80)
      - Minutes of meetings, 1950-1955
      - "Small Companies", 1951
    - T.E. Tatum re A naconda Wire and Cable Co., 1929-1960 (Box 15:81)
    - Transfer of assets - Holmes, Booth and Haydens to Benedict & Burnham Mfg. Co., 1905 (Box 15:82)
    - Quitclaims (Box 15:83)
      - American Flask & Cap Co., 1857, 1959
      - Mahan Manufacturing Co., 1851-1853
      - Waterbury Water Power Co., 1848-1951
  - Subseries F: Annual Reports, 1895-1959
    - American Brass Company, 1900-1922 (Box 16)
    - American Brass Company and Anaconda American Brass, Ltd., 1953-1959 (Box 17)
    - Anaconda Copper Mining Company, 1895-1924 (Box 18)
  - Subseries G: Charter and Bylaws, 1900-1967
    - Anaconda American Brass Company
      - Bylaws, 1900, 1963-1965 (Box 19:84)
      - Charter, resolutions, correspondence and related documents, 1960, 1967 (Box 19:85)
- Series III: Sales Department Files, undated, 1853-1970
  - Allocation of Territory Register, 1937 (Box 20:86)
  - Allocation of Territory Register, 1951, 1954 (Box 20:87)
  - Base Prices
    - Master set 1-2, 1939-1947 (Box 20:88)
    - Master set 3-6, 1939-1947 (Box 20:89)
    - Master set 7-10, 1939-1947 (Box 20:90)
    - Master set 11-16, 1939-1947 (Box 20:91)
    - Master set 32-37, 1939-1947 (Box 20:92)
  - Catalogs--American Brass
    - 1912-1925 (Box 21:93)
    - 1925-1930 (Box 21:94)
    - 1930-1934 (Box 21:95)
    - 1934 (Box 21:96)
    - 1940 (Box 21:97)
    - With revisions, 1948-1961 (Box 22:98)
  - Customer account cards, undated (Box 22:99)
  - Customer account cards, undated (Box 22:100)
  - Contracts, Master set, 1935 (Box 22:101)
  - Copper tube fitting prices, 1953 (Box 22:102)
  - Everdur products, 1933-1934 (Box 22:103)
  - Everdur products, 1934 (Box 22:104)
  - Miscellaneous sales materials (Box 22:105)
    - Benedict Nickel brochure, undated
    - Blank sales charts, 1970
    - Canadian Duties on Non-Ferrous Materials, 1937, 1941
    - Data table, 1935
    - Instructions for steam engine indicator, 1893
    - Prices to Distributors, 1937
    - Sales summary, 1935-1939
    - Waterbury Brass Co., List showing stock of brass and copper, 1902
  - Price Books (Box 23)
    - American Brass Company, 1903-1914
    - Anaconda, 1923-1934
    - Ansonia Bass and Battery Co., 1862-1905
    - Benedict and Burnham Manufacturing Co., 1892-1911
    - Benedict and Burnham Manufacturing Co., 1892-1911 (Box 24)
    - Birmingham Brass Co., 1898
    - Bridgeport Brass Co., 1913
    - Chicago Brass Co., 1898
    - Coe Brass Co., 1894-1913
    - Delta Metal Co. Ltd., undated
    - Detroit Copper and Brass Rolling Mills Co., 1908-1924
    - Elliot's Metal Co., undated
    - French Manufacturing Co., 1907
    - Holmes Booth and Haydens Co., 1897-1906
    - John A. Roeblings' Sons Co., 1897
    - National Cable and Conduit Co., 1922
    - Phosphor Bronze Smelting Co., 1904
    - Randolf-Clowes Co., 1892-1912
    - Unidentified, 1894-1908
    - Waterbury Brass Co., 1876-1911
  - Price Change information, 1942-1955 (Box 25:106)
  - Price Lists
    - 1913-1919 (Box 25:107)
    - 1919-1920 (Box 25:108)
    - 1920-1923 (Box 25:109)
    - 1925-1930 (Box 25:110)
    - 1931-1933 (Box 25:111)
    - 1934-1935 (Box 26:112)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 26:113)
    - 1937 (Box 26:114)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 26:115)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 26:116)
    - 1949-1956 (Box 26:117)
  - Price Schedules, 1931-1936 (Box 27:118)
    - Schedule 1 - Catalog, 1948-1961 (Box 27:119)
    - Schedule 1A, 1D - Price lists, 1949-1961 (Box 27:120)
    - Schedule 1R, 1S, 1Sa, 1W, 1940-1960 (Box 27:121)
    - Schedule 2, 2Ds - Price lists, 1940-1960 (Box 27:122)
    - Schedule 3 - Prices, 1940-1960 (Box 27:123)
    - Schedule 3D - Price lists, 1940-1960 (Box 28:124)
    - Schedule 3D - Price lists, 1940-1960 (Box 28:125)
    - Schedule 3M, 4 - Price lists, 1940-1960 (Box 28:126)
    - Schedule 5-5D - Prices, 1940-1960 (Box 28:127)
    - Schedule 6 - Prices, 1940-1960 (Box 28:128)
    - Schedule 7, 7D, 1940-1960 (Box 28:129)
    - Schedule 8, 9, 9C, 1940-1960 (Box 28:130)
    - Schedule 10, 10A, 11 - Prices, 1940-1960 (Box 29:131)
    - Schedule 12 - Prices, 1940-1960 (Box 29:132)
    - Schedule 12D - Price list, 1940-1960 (Box 29:133)
    - Schedule 13-15 - Prices, 1940-1960 (Box 29:134)
    - Schedule 16-18D - Prices, 1940-1960 (Box 29:135)
    - Schedule 23-24, 50 - Prices, 1940-1960 (Box 29:136)
    - Schedule ALB, BCN, BWN - Prices, 1940-1960 (Box 29:137)
  - Productos de Cobre y Laton (Spanish version), 1924 (Box 30:138)
  - Promotional Material, 1912-1947 (Box 30:139)
  - Revisions, 1930-1937 (Box 30:140)
  - Revisions, 1933-1940 (Box 30:141)
  - Sales Information Bulletin, 1935-1938 (Box 30:142)
  - Sales Information Bulletin, 1939-1941 (Box 30:143)
  - Sales Information Letters, 1941-1948 (Box 30:144)
  - Sales Notebooks of Frank H. Hoffman, 1892 (Box 30:145)
  - Schedule of extras, 1933 (Box 31:146)
  - Specifications, ca. 1900, 1947 (Box 31:147)
  - Statement of Sales, 1863-1922 (Box 31:148)
  - Statement of earnings, 1906-1909 (Box 31:149)
  - Statement of earnings, 1910-1915 (Box 31:150)
  - Statement of earnings, 1916-1920 (Box 31:151)
  - Statement of earnings, 1921-1923 (Box 31:152)
  - Pension Reports, 1907-1923 (Box 32:153)
  - Yearly Reports, 1923-1938 (Box 32:154)
  - Yearly Reports, 1938-1944 (Box 32:155)
  - "9th Victory Loan Campaign" Scrapbook, 1944 (Box 32:156)
  - "Mr. Brooker's Scrapbook" Coe Mfg., 1867-1908 (Box 33)
  - Price list books, 1913-1939 (Box 33)
  - R.T. Benedict's personal price list book, 1915-1935 (Box 33)
  - Scrapbook of price lists, 1853-1874 (Box 33)
  - Anaconda Copper and Copper Alloys Data Book, 1950 (Box 34)
  - Handbook for Brass, Bronze, Copper, Nickel, Silver, 1935 (Box 34)
  - Price list books, 1912-1935 (Box 34)
  - ABC, Sales department price change records, 1904-1915 (Box 35)
  - Anaconda American Brass Co. tax rates, 1965 (Box 35)
  - George Benham notes on American Metal Market, 1914-1923 (Box 35)
  - Handwritten sales records, 1855-1856 (Box 35)
  - War Production Board, Copper division, Brass Mill Branch, WWII operations, 1914-1923, 1945 (Box 35)
- Series IV: Library Ephemera Files, undated, 1642-1966
  - Subseries A: Subject files, undated, ca. 1800-1960
    - Historical Subject Files--A - El (Box 36:157)
      - Advertising expenditures, 1914
      - Anaconda-Jurden Associates Inc., 1961
      - American Cap and Flask, undated
      - Articles and reprints, 1939-1952
        - American Brass from Sheel Progress, 1939
        - Article about American Brass and its subsidiaries, 1951
        - Development of the Brass Industry, 1939
        - One Hundred Years of Manufacturing Brass, undated
      - Awards, 1959
      - Beryllium Copper, Monopoly hearing, 1939
      - Birthdays of executive officers, undated
      - Bibliography of ABC, undated
      - Century of Brass Making ABC and E.T. Ingham, 1922
      - Charter of American Brass, 1936
      - Chilean Congressional delegation-visit to ABC, 1958
      - Color Advertisements, 1959
      - "Copper and Brass Industry organization" C.B. Jacobs, 1937
      - Copper brochure-ABC, undated
      - "Crypt of Civilization", ca. 1933
      - Daguerreotypes-notes, 1940
      - Development of the Brass Industry in Connecticut, Tertiary Commission, State of CT, 1936
      - "Early history of Brass Making in Waterbury", 1932
      - Electro-Sheet Copper-ABC, 1922-1959
    - Historical Subject Files--Em - F (Box 36:158)
      - Employee benefits, 1913-1956
      - Executive organization, 1899-1955
      - Extrusion process-ABC, 1883-1914
      - Family Tree-ABC, 1829-1923
      - Financial report to Litchfield Cty and Naugatuck Valley, 1949-1954
      - Flood recovery-ABC, 1956
    - Historical Subject Files--G - M (Box 36:159)
      - Genealogy of the Naugatuck Brass Industry, 1946
      - General Office hours, 1902-1960
      - Golf lots sale-ABC, 1958-1959
      - Good Neighbor policy visit, 1944
      - Group Insurance, Anaconda Copper Mining Co., 1945
      - Highway Association, undated
      - History of American Brass, books about, 1922-1955
      - Holding to Operating Company, 1912
      - Hospital-ABC, 1914-1944
      - Journals, ledgers and record book inventory sheet, undated
      - Kettles-ABC, ca. 1960
      - Lamp burners-ABC, 1952
      - Library-ABC, 1939-1959
      - Library Correspondence, 1940, 1952
      - Merger with Anaconda, 1921-1930
      - Miscellaneous, undated
      - Mural presented to YMCA, 1951
    - Historical Subject Files--Na (Box 36:160)
      - Name change to Anaconda American Brass, 1960
      - Navy "E" Awards-WWII, 1940s
    - Historical Subject Files--Ne (Box 36:161)
      - News - The American Brass Company, 1950s
      - Newspaper Articles, 1940-1960
        - Awards
        - Closures and damages
        - Community Service
        - Company policy changes
        - Employees
        - Exhibits
        - Expansions
        - Historical articles
        - Product development
    - Historical Subject Files--N.R.A., 1933-1934 (Box 36:162)
    - Historical Subject Files--O - P (Box 36:163)
      - Officers and Directors, 1937-1960
      - Order Entry manual-ABC, 1953
      - Patents-ABC, 1936-1943
      - Personnel Development Program-ABC, 1956, 1959
      - Pipe, 1950
      - Price and data catalogs, list of, ca. 1800
    - Historical Subject Files--R - Se (Box 37:164)
      - Records, Preservation of, 1948-1958
      - Research Center-ABC, 1960
      - Rocky Mountain Club-ABC, 1928
      - Sales organization, 1955, 1957
      - Sales organization personnel, 1953-1958
      - Second Annual Clerk's outing, 1907
      - Service Award certificates, 1950
      - Service Award dinners, 1957-1960
      - Service Statistics, 1958
    - Historical Subject Files--Sp - W (Box 37:165)
      - Speech for John Coe, undated
      - Strike-ABC, 1946
      - Vocabulary for Trainees, 1949
      - Want list, 1940
      - Waterbury Almanac excerpts, 1853-1871
      - Water Wheel-ABC, 1951
      - Welcome to American Brass, 1960
      - Woodlot business-ABC, 1954
      - World War II-assignment completed, 1946
      - World War II file, 1939-1945
  - Suberies B: Division histories, undated, 1642-1960
    - Ansonia Branch (Box 37:166)
      - Advertisement, 1925
      - Ansonia Brass and Copper, 1952-1960
      - Ansonia Brass and Copper/Phelps Dodge, 1800-1913
      - Ansonia O&C Company, 1847-1892
      - Birmingham Brass Company, 1960
      - Coe Brass Manufacturing Co., 1868-1869, 1907-1918
      - Continuous Casting, 1958
      - Copper Wire history, 1926-1957
      - Electric lights, 1931-1959
      - Electric Street Railway line, 1888, 1937-1941
      - Farmer, Moses G., 1826-1892
      - Kinneytown Dam, 1911-1956
      - Newsletter - Installation of new equipment, 1959
      - Newspaper clippings, 1942-1961
      - Officers, 1912
      - "Oilways", 1953
      - Orcutt, Samuel "History of Derby" excerpt, 1642-1880
      - Miscellaneous, 1949-1961
      - Osborne and Cheeseman, 1810-1880
      - Service Award dinners, 1957-1959
      - Stapak fibre drums, undated
      - Wallace and Sons, 1797-1960
    - Buffalo Branch (Box 37:167)
      - Balance sheet, 1913
      - Branch history records, 1906-1917
      - Estimated profits, 1912
      - Expenses, 1911
      - Library correspondence, 1940
      - List of machinery and equipment, 1912
      - Mill proposal, undated
      - Mills, 1950-1960
      - Operations, 1910
      - Photographs (relocated to photograph series), undated
      - Service awards, 1958-1959
      - Statement of assets and liabilities, 1911-1912
    - Detroit Branch (Box 37:167)
      - Plates for large surface condensers, 1960
      - Promotion of R.E. Puffer, 1960
      - Service Awards dinners, 1956-1959
    - Fabricated Metal Goods (Box 37:167)
      - American Flask & Cap Co., 1863-1940
      - Newspaper clippings, 1956
      - Service Award dinners, 1956-1959
      - Waterbury Brass Goods Corp., 1907-1956
    - Kenosha Branch (Box 37:168)
      - Appreciation award, 1956
      - Chicago Brass Company history, 1905-1957
      - Equipment information, 1955
      - Newspaper clippings, 1941-1956
      - Open House, 1956
      - Robberies, 1950
      - Service Awards dinners, 1957-1959
      - Trade magazine excerpts, 1958
    - Los Angeles Division (Box 37:169)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1957
      - Open house, 1958
      - Press release, 1955
      - Promotional material, 1955-1958
      - Receiving numbers, 1958
    - Small Tube Division (Box 37:169)
      - Awards, 1953
      - French Arrowhead newsletter, 1956
      - Name change, 1960
      - Newspaper clippings, 1957-1960
      - Officers, 1930
      - Service Award dinners, 1956-1959
    - Torrington Branch (Box 37:170)
      - Branch announcements, 1959-1961
      - History, 1935
      - Mill closure, 1961
      - Coe Brass Manufacturing Co., 1907-1955
      - Family Day, 1956
      - Hendey Machine Co. Property, 1954-1960
      - Newspaper clippings, 1907, 1944-1959
      - Periodical excerpts, 1957, 1959
      - Service Awards dinners, 1957
      - Telephones, 1942
      - Torrington, CT history, 1905-1948
      - Wolcottville Brass Co., 1960
    - Waterbury Division (Box 38:171)
      - Awards, 1957
      - Benedict & Burnham Manufacturing Co., 1861-1950
      - Family Day, 1956
      - Family Day, South plant, 1956
      - Holmes, Booth and Haydens, 1956-1960
      - "Multiple Plunger Press", 1911
      - Newspaper clippings, 1945-1959
      - "Oilways" excerpt, 1944
      - Randolph and Clowes Co., 1955
      - River Company, 1949
      - Service Awards, 1956-1959
      - Water Wheel, 1941-1951
      - Waterbury Brass Company, 1907-1956
    - District offices, Warehouses (Box 38:172)
      - Cedar Rapids, IA, 1956-1958
      - Charlotte, NC, 1957
      - Chicago, IL, 1952
      - Cincinnati, OH, 1957
      - Cleveland, OH, 1956-1959
      - Philadelphia, PA, 1957
      - Directory of offices and branches, 1949
  - Subseries C: Anaconda and subsidiaries, undated, 1891-1961
    - Anaconda (Box 38:173)
      - Advertisement, undated
      - Aluminum, 1951
      - Articles
        - Bulger, Niel J., "The Anaconda Story", 1948
        - Marcosson, Isaac, "Anaconda", 1957
        - Solow, Herbert, "Anaconda, One Face to The Future", 1955
      - Andes Copper Mining Co., 1929
      - Annual meetings, 1959
      - Awards, 1957, 1959
      - Bibliography for students and/or the Anaconda Copper Mining Co., 1952
      - Butte Community Memorial Hospital, 1950-1951
      - Butte, MT, 1956
      - Christmas party, undated
      - Chuquicamata, Chile, 1952-1957
      - Columbia Falls, MT, 1957
      - Copper, 1929
      - Copper Supply, 1951
      - Development and growth, 1960
      - Earnings, 1957-1958
      - El Salvador Mine, 1959-1960
      - Emma Mine, 1956
    - (Box 38:174)
      - Forest Fires, undated
      - "From Mine to Consumer", undated
      - Grants, NM, 1958-1961
      - Greater Butte Project, 1950-1951
      - Historical dates, 1895-1959
      - Income, 1958-1961
      - Iron Ore Project, 1957-1959
      - Map of Operations, 1958-1959
      - Mining Operations, 1958-1959
      - Montana, undated
      - Newspaper clippings, 1947-1959
      - Periodical excerpts, 1937-1961
    - (Box 38:175)
      - Raritan Copper Works ( Perth Amboy, NJ), undated
      - Reduction department, undated
      - Reduction Works, ca. 1930
      - Speeches given by John A. Coe, 1954, 1957
      - Strike, 1959-1960
      - "What happened in Butte?", 1948
    - Anaconda Aluminum Company (Box 38:176)
      - American Aluminum, 1959-1960
      - Cochran Foil Company, 1957-1960
      - Columbia Falls, MT, 1955-1959